Good morning.
Someone asked me to greet you, "Happy Birthday!"
I was asking Him, "why do You ask me to greet people of God 'Happy Birthday'?"
He said, "Wednesday is Emmanuel TV's birthday".
Emmanuel TV will be 11 years old. Happy Birthday!
Hallelujah.
Viewers all over the world, Happy Birthday!
Your Emmanuel TV will be 11 years old.
Hallelujah
Wow
Jesus knows many of us here will repent because you are a true 'born-again'.
How do we know you are a true 'born-again'?
We know you are a true 'born-again' when each time you miss the mark, you run to God
because you are a true 'born-again'.
Is it not a joyful thing for you?
I can’t see your joy.
It is a prophesy.
This is a message from Heaven.
Jesus says He knows you will repent because you are a true 'born-again'.
Amen.
You know, when is a true 'born-again', you can only miss the mark; you cannot sin if your adoption is genuine.
If you are a true 'born-again', nothing can separate you from God.
You can only miss the mark; you cannot sin.
The wrong becomes sin when you refuse to repent.
When you refuse to repent it becomes a sin.
How do we know a true 'born-again'?
We know a true 'born-again' when each time he misses the mark, he runs to God.
I'm sorry.
It is over.
That is truly 'born-again' -
he is connected.
His position cannot be displaced; it's always there.
He can only leave the position for a while and come back.
Hallelujah
Talk on faith.
Let someone say, "talk on faith".
Yes.
We have many books to read.
I will take the book of Hebrews which seems to be very appropriate, close to what we are about to talk.
Hebrews 4.
I will take my reading from verse 1, and the proof test will be verse 3 there.
"Therefore, since the promise of entering his rest still stands, let us be careful
that none of you be found to have fallen short of it."
None of you be found fallen for short of glory, grace...
Hebrews 4:2, "For we also have had the good news proclaimed to us, just as they did;
but the message they heard was of no value to them,
because they did not share the faith of those who obeyed."
Verse 3, "Now we who have believed enter that rest, just as God has said."
Those who believed enter that rest.
It means faith and rest cannot be separated from one another.
Whenever our heart truly believes, it will always be at rest.
If our hearts are uneasy and restless, if we are afraid of this or that,
if we are struggling with all our effort to plan, resolve, plead or ask for help,
this shows that we have not yet believed.
When one truly believes, he is at rest.
When a person believes, he will no longer worry.
When you truly believe Jesus, you will no longer worry.
Take note of that.
Faith does not come by force.
Anything that comes by force is not faith.
Faith is something that comes spontaneously, naturally.
Something that comes spontaneously.
For example, if we see a man, a person, we know he is there.
We don’t need to struggle to believe.
That is faith.
Within a second, we believe spontaneously.
I am just giving you the picture of faith.
There are all kinds of faith.
Faith in faith, faith in ourselves, faith in "such of nature", faith in this...
I have faith in business...
We use the word "faith" in business.
I have faith in you, I have faith you will do the job, I know by faith, all kinds of faith.
That is not the faith in God.
If you have faith in God, you should not just believe in Him.
Today, we claim we believe but where is our faith?
Faith is practical.
What we do expresses what we believe.
It is purely practical.
The reality of faith can only be proved by practice.
Have faith in God; all things are possible.
Have faith in God.
The reality of faith can only be proved by practice.
We should not merely talk about faith; we should put it into practice.
Faith is a conviction.
It’s a demonstration.
Have faith in God.
Today, people don’t know how to believe and express their faith.
Many people say they believe;
I believe Jesus...
If you believe Jesus, where is your faith?
Not only should we know God as our Sovereign Lord; we should know Him like children know their father.
Take note,
not only should we know God as our Sovereign Lord; we should know Him like children know their father.
How do children know their father?
Good children depend on their father.
Good children know how much they love their father.
Good children know how much they need their father.
That are good children.
Faith can be applied.
This is an application.
You can say, "I believe" because you know you cannot show that belief.
We hide under that belief.
Faith can be applied.
We can apply all of God's blessings through faith and make them manifest in us.
Have faith in God.
The Bible is full of promises.
For every matter, there are promises that God will do for us as long as we have faith.
God will listen to us as long as we have faith.
One without faith is dead.
Faith without works is dead in the same way.
How many of us can stand to say, "I know God like children know their father"?
No.
You only know Him as a Sovereign Lord.
He owns the world, He is a father of invisible and visible, that's all.
The question – how should one have faith in God?
We have faith in God through the daily things around us.
In Jesus' name.
See me, I want to talk - "in Jesus' name", I want to raise my hand - "in Jesus' name", I want to greet
I will mention Jesus.
I want to cough - I call Jesus before I cough.
I want to dress up.
Before raising my hand I need to call Jesus to help me - Jesus.
I want to comb my hair.
Before making an effort - Jesus.
Because faith is practical.
Like children know their father; children depend on their father for everything.
Daddy, mummy - they depend on their father for everything.
There is nothing good children want to do on their own.
Good children.
They will call their daddy for everything.
You are His children.
The Bible calls us children.
We children - greater is He that is in us.
He never called you an adult.
He never called you "baba".
He never called you "mumma" but you are the one calling yourself "mumma".
Mumma, baba, daddy - those names do not enter Heaven.
In Heaven they know you as children.
You can continue to enjoy being called different names; father, mumma, baba, sister, uncle, this, that,
pastor, prophet - you enjoy it.
But when you get there you are children.
Because of those different names being used you think that you can do things yourself.
That is the problem you are having today.
Before God, you are a child.
Total dependence on God.
When you want to eat - Jesus.
When you want to wash your hands - Jesus.
When you want to comb your hair - Jesus.
When you want to wear your spectacles - Jesus.
When you want to sit down - Jesus.
When you want to stand up - Jesus.
When you want to take a bath - Jesus.
You want to dress - Jesus.
You want to greet, before you say "How are you?", you call Jesus
What is the name by which they know you in Heaven?
We are known as children of God.
Thank you.
So, mumma - your child is calling you, that is getting to your head.
Yes.
Because of that you believe that you can tie your hair on your own.
Mummy, mummy.
Yes, sir. I believe.
What do you need to do now?
I need to realise... even to humble myself the more.
Before the God I am a child.
What do you need to do as a child?
I have to behave as a child and try to know my Father.
OK, can somebody help?
To depend entirely on Him, as He is the Father.
How does a child depend on the Father?
By having faith in Him, not believing that He would fail.
Rest - when your Father is around, knowing that He takes care of you.
Can somebody say it in a simple form?
Who are you now to God?
I'm a child of God.
You are a child of God?
Not a father of God, like your children call you?
I'm a child of God.
Not a father?
No.
Not an uncle?
Not a brother?
No.
Not the MD of the company?
Not the general overseer of the Synagogue?
No.
We need to know ourselves.
This is the problem we have today.
No.
Viewers at home, listen to me.
Nobody will preach this without a revelation.
It is a pure revelation.
I am coming out with a revelation that will solve your problem.
Revelation that will solve your problem.
Before your children - father, before your uncle - brother, before anybody - this, MD of the company -
I am the richest, general overseer, all this here - in the world.
But think of God - we are children.
If we are children of God, what is the position of a child to the father?
Total dependence!
When you want to talk - Jesus - before you talk.
When you want to run - Jesus.
Children cannot do anything on their own.
Can a child do anything on his own?
No.
That is you!
It’s a deep revelation. People have gone astray in the world.
Total dependence upon Him – you must know how much you need Him
just like your children at home need you.
Good children, not bad children.
We have some bad children.
When you are not at home, little children would open your pot and eat your soup.
Total dependence upon Him – to talk, look, dress and do everything.
Forget about your pride in this world, the honour you receive from you children.
Members of your church would call you prophet, bishop, this, that, general overseer...
Sometimes, when I'm going you call me "general overseer of the Synagogue" - I don't listen to you.
Because I know...
Vanity upon vanity.
The general is in Heaven, I'm not a general.
I know you want to kill me.
Not only should we know God as our Sovereign Lord; we should know Him like children know their father.
Do you actually know Him like children know their father?
You praise Him, you adore Him, you worship Him, you dance, you defend Him, everywhere you say,
"Jesus is the only Lord, He is the Redeemer, He is Savior".
There is nothing you cannot say about Jesus.
Even you begin to defend and begin to say, "I'm a Christian, I'm born-again"...
Are you really sure you know Jesus like children know their father?
You read the Bible from Genesis to Revelation.
There is no verse you cannot quote, or refer to.
You can combat a battle, you can face anyone quoting the Bible.
You have a degree, you have a level...
There is no tittle we do not have.
We are prophets, bishops, we are that and that...
Do you know Him like children know their father?
Back to who we are – you are a child of God.
Anywhere you introduce yourself, you say, “I am a child of God”.
You say you are a father of God.
Do you ever say you are a father of God?
How do you introduce yourself?
As a child of God.
Why can’t you behave like a child to Him?
Why do you behave like a mumma to God?
Are you the one who gave birth to God?
No.
But the way you behave...
You only run to Him when you have difficulty or challenges.
You don’t know how much you need Him.
If you are a child of God, why can’t you know Him like children know their father?
The word "faith" is about this.
What is faith?
Faith is a heart that believes God through ordinary circumstances.
I need God to sit down, stand up, take my bath, dress up and wear my spectacles.
If you can carry God along in those ordinary issues, tell me big issue - you will slip on His what?
The best way to live life is what I'm telling you today.
You are a child of God, why can’t you behave like a child to Him?
Behave like a child of God.
It is not too late.
You must know how much you need Him.
You need Him to sit down, you need Him to eat, you need Him to drink, you need Him to sleep,
you need Him to wake up, you need Him to greet.
You need Him even to put on your spectacles - you cannot do it yourself.
Say, "I cannot do it".
I cannot wear it myself, wear it for me God.
I'm a child.
Let someone say, "I'm a child".
Wear my spectacles for me.
You need this strength.
You think this strength is yours - it is not yours.
You are fake.
You think you have strength, you can wear spectacles by yourself - it's God's strength but you fail to recognize it.
When an attack comes, and the hand is paralyzed, you will recognize God.
I never knew it was Your strength.
All this time I thought it was my strength.
Anytime you want to wear your spectacles you just pick it.
You fail to know that it is God's strength, but you will know this when an attack comes.
When satat attacks, and the hand is paralyzed, you will begin to ask God for a deliverance, healing.
You would say, "Help me God. Let me move" - you recognize Him.
Please - don't wait for that.
Say, “It’s Your strength Lord.”
It’s Your strength Lord
to sit.
It’s Your strength to stand.
It’s Your strength to greet.
It’s Your strength to look, sleep, love and to do all.
Start your Christian life from there.
There are many preachers here.
Preachers, sitting down here.
If I gave them the microphone to preach, nobody would listen to me.
They are on their seats.
My brothers - let us close our Bibles, let's listen to the revelation.
It is only a revelation that can solve our problem.
What can solve our problem?
Revelation.
I cannot hear you.
Look, this Bible, before it becomes revelation to you, you must first meditate it.
By meditation, revelation comes out of it.
For now it is the Bible.
For this Bible to become revelation, you must meditate it.
By meditation and turning it over and over, in your heart, it becomes a revelation.
Meditation turns to revelation.
Meditation on what you read, turn it over and over in your heart...
To turn something in your heart, you know when something is going in your heart,
it's going through what?
This thing.
Go over and over in your heart - that becomes a revelation.
The process of turning over in your heart is no longer in your mouth.
Then it can affect you, become a "character".
Let me use an example of the Bible - anyone can but it.
When you get to the market they will never ask you, "Are you a Christian?" before giving you a copy.
All they need is money.
That is to tell you - you make it work.
If you are a bad person your Bible is also bad.
If you are good your Bible is good.
That is why everybody has access to it.
Now - to make it a revelation, it must go through a meditation in your heart.
It must go through what?
Meditation.
Meditation can only occur in our heart.
Remember, there is a difference between meditation and thinking.
Meditation is a higher level, while thinking is a lower level.
Upper class, lower class.
When you are worried, you are thinking.
You never worry and meditate.
Until you are free of worry, then you can meditate.
Tell your neighbour, “I’m a child of God – total dependence on Him;
I should know how much I need Him.
I need Him to do everything, even to talk or look I need Him."
I need You more and more
I need You more and more Jesus every day
Like a flower needs the rain
Like a bird needs the wind
I need You more and more Jesus every day
I need You more and more
More
I need You more and more Jesus every day
I need You more and more
More
Lord, I need You more and more
I need You more and more Jesus every day
You may be seated. Thank You, Lord.
I want you to write it in your book.
Today, you are a child of God and you should behave like a child to the father.
You are a child of God.
I said, "you may be seated" - you sat without even carrying God along.
You have forgotten because you are used to those your fake power.
Because you are a child, you need God to do all.
You introduce yourself as a child of God but you behave otherwise.
This why we see people who claim to believe, who don't know how to believe and express their faith.
What we do expresses what we believe.
If there is faith, there must be work that corresponds with that faith.
Faith is expressed through work.
By this work, faith is perfected.
By this work, faith is proved.
By this work, faith is completed.
If faith and work do not agree, there must be something wrong with our faith.
It is either faith in faith or faith in ourselves.
Self righteousness.
I repeat.
If faith and work do not agree, there must be something wrong with our faith.
It is either faith in faith or faith in ourselves.
Faith in what man has done: science, knowledge, just mention it.
What we have faith in is what man has done - it is what we have faith in.
Sometimes, when we enter a church we can see the crowd, we see a beautiful church - we have faith in it.
Oh, big church, many wonderful people, president - that is enough for our faith.
Or the way ministers of God preach, "I tell you - God is love" - it is a good preacher.
That is enough for our faith.
This can be regarded as "what man has done".
Faith in the finished work of our Lord, Jesus Christ has to do with the supernatural.
Faith is practical.
It is as simple as a conviction.
It can not be expressed in abstracts.
That is why today people hide under the "belief" - I believe in Christ, I'm a believer...
The word "faith" has to do with a trust.
Finally – our work proves our faith.
What is your work?
Your work proves your faith.
Your work perfects your faith.
Because faith works together with its work.
I'm talking to the children of God.
Are you a child of God?
Yes.
I cannot hear you.
Just recognize that you are a child.
And you know what a child needs from a father.
It is a total dependence.
There is nothing a child can do without the father.
You only call Him when an attack comes.
That is why He doesn't rescue you.
He knows you are calling Him for selfish reasons.
What are selfish reasons? It is just to rescue you.
After rescuing you, you will start living your own life - and He doesn't want that.
He wants your whole life, not a part of your life.
Go, and think about this.